<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>第二章：遊戲基礎 on 蒙面少俠 中文站</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/</link><description>Recent content in 第二章：遊戲基礎 on 蒙面少俠 中文站</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>遊戲就是一場對話</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/conversation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/conversation/</guid><description>THE CONVERSATION
#
Playing MASKS is having a conversation. That means it’s easy! You sit at the table with dice and pencils and sheets of paper, and you talk with each other. For the most part, the conversation revolves around your characters. You say what they do and how they react. Since the other players don’t live in your head, you convey your character’s thoughts, emotions, and feelings to the other players and the GM.</description></item><item><title>開始遊戲之前</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/starting-the-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/starting-the-game/</guid><description>開始遊戲之前
#
在你遊玩《蒙面少俠》之前，你需要先準備好一些東西，也需要先考慮好一些議題。
準備遊玩
#
You need a space to play. If you’re playing face-to-face, you want a table big enough for everybody to sit around it, spread out a bit, put their character sheets down, and roll dice. Make sure you’ve got printed copies of the basic moves and the playbooks ready to go, along with a pair of dice for each player, some tokens for tracking Influence, a batch of index cards or post-its, and a bunch of pencils.</description></item><item><title>描述場景</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/framing-scene/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/framing-scene/</guid><description>FRAMING SCENES
#
The best way to keep the conversation moving toward interesting places is to frame scenes. Instead of sitting around the table talking vaguely about cool characters, who they are, and what they can do, put those characters into concrete locations with concrete objectives. You don’t just say, “Oh yeah, Nano’s got nanite powers, so he can make weapons out of the nanites in his body!” You put Nano into the Exemplars’ Headquarters and describe him sending his nanites into the nearby machines and taking over the security system.</description></item><item><title>為什麼要玩這個遊戲？</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/why-play/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-basics/why-play/</guid><description>為什麼要玩這個遊戲？
#
But why do this? Why go to all this work to tell a story, when TV, movie theaters, and even book stores are full of superhero stories you can consume without having to do any of the work to write them yourself?
Because it’s frickin’ awesome!
Because when you play MASKS, you create your own cool superheroes, interesting and competent and powerful and capable of heading up their own comic books.</description></item></channel></rss>