<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>第九章：引鉤與故事弧 on 蒙面少俠 中文站</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/</link><description>Recent content in 第九章：引鉤與故事弧 on 蒙面少俠 中文站</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>引鉤與故事弧</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/about/</guid><description>HOOKS AND ARCS
#
When you run MASKS, you’ll inevitably have an impulse to plan stories in advance. Maybe you think one of the PCs should choose to leave the team for a corporate sponsored team that turns out to be a trap set in motion by the Dread Queen, eventually discovering the trap but ultimately overcoming it thanks to their new teammates. All that has to happen is for the PC to choose to leave the team and fall into the trap, right?</description></item><item><title>創造與使用引鉤</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/the-hooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/the-hooks/</guid><description>BUILDING HOOKS
#
Each hook is an actual character that pulls a PC towards a Label. Pairs of hooks are always focused on one PC, in particular on the two Labels by which they might be defined. The simplest way to come up with a pair of hooks for a PC is to ask: “Is (PC) a (Label) or (Label)?”
Think of this question as if you’re a reader of your game’s comic book series.</description></item><item><title>創造與使用故事弧</title><link>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/the-arcs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hazmole.github.io/masks-zh-release/docs/rules/the-hooks-and-arcs/the-arcs/</guid><description>創造故事弧
#
The plans of villains and antagonists in Halcyon City are sometimes as simple as, “Rob a bank!” “Steal a McGuffin!” But the PCs also have to save the city from grander, more dangerous, more dramatic threats, problems that span across multiple issues of your comic and multiple sessions of your game. Those threats and problems are your arcs.
Each arc has a cast of NPCs and other fictional elements (places and objects of importance), an arc type, and three phases.</description></item></channel></rss>